<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/learning/</link><description>Recent content in Learning on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prepare for the Azure Cybersecurity Architect SC-100 exam</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Frustration!&lt;/strong> If one word should describe the learning experience using Microsoft Learn (other words could have been: indigestable, wut?!, uncohesive etcetera). I have never encountered a Microsoft Learning path that was so hard to digest.
Then you could ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Is the subject that hard?&amp;rdquo;. It is not the subject, it is the way the self-study was written. In this blog post, I will share the way I prepared for this exam.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Just do it! Work on your certifications.</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 15:08:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you asked me 5 years ago if I would do any Microsoft exam, I would have told you that getting certified is something that you need to do at the start of your career. Besides that I would have told you that once your work experience and technical influence increases, you can rely on your seniority. I have to admit that for a long time I could get away with using the correct buzzwords at the correct moment supported by a certain arrogance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Techorama Antwerp 2022, human connection</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</guid><description>&lt;p>Techorama is a conference that has long been on my list of conferences to attend, but for some reason I never went. Looking back I think I had this idea that world class conferences could only be held in the US (or in a place far-far away from home) with thousands of visitors. I was dead wrong.
What the organizers understood perfectly is that in order to have a world class conference, you should offer the same smooth, convenient and rich experience with the very best speakers, but then at a smaller scale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Certification Renewal</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</guid><description>&lt;p>When Microsoft introduced the new role based certifaction paths, a new expiration policy was set as well. After two years (as of july 2021, one year) the certification will expire, and you have to renew it in order to keep it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time, I was among the first people who passed the new certifications and back then the new expiration policy was unclear. There was no information on how to renew the certifications and costs involved, until a few weeks ago&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>