<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>doepicshit on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/doepicshit/</link><description>Recent content in doepicshit on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/doepicshit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Techorama Antwerp 2022, human connection</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</guid><description>Techorama is a conference that has long been on my list of conferences to attend, but for some reason I never went. Looking back I think I had this idea that world class conferences could only be held in the US with thousands of visitors (in a place far-far away from home). I was dead wrong. What the organizers understood perfectly is that in order to have a world class conference, you should offer the same smooth, convenient and rich experience with the very best speakers, but then at a smaller scale.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>You have found my personal blog. This blog will be focused around Microsoft Azure technologies, hence the name &amp;ldquo;something Azure&amp;rdquo;. Let me introduce myself, my name is Bas van de Sande and I work as an Azure Coding Architect at Xpirit in the Netherlands.
As part of my daily job, I offer technical guidance, advice and hands-on assistance for a large number of (global) companies in various industries.
I have been working with Microsoft technologies since 1995 in various technical roles, since that time I have seen a large number of technologies passing by (Visual Studio technologies, SQL Server, BizTalk, Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>