<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/</link><description>Recent content on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prepare for the Azure Cybersecurity Architect SC-100 exam</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</guid><description>Frustration! If one word should describe the learning experience using Microsoft Learn (other words could have been: indigestable, wut?!, uncohesive etcetera). I have never encountered a Microsoft Learning path that was so hard to digest. Then you could ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Is the subject that hard?&amp;rdquo;. It is not the subject, it is the way the self-study was written. In this blog post, I will share the way I prepared for this exam.</description></item><item><title>Project Volterra - Windows Dev Kit 2023 - take 1</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/volterra-take1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 13:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/volterra-take1/</guid><description>At Xpirit we have an Innovation Day multiple times per year. The idea of an Innovation Day is to work on technologies or topics that spark your interest. Anything is allowed, as long as it has nothing to do with any customer assignments. Learning and knowledge sharing is the goal of such a day.
At our last Innovation Day in november, I picked up the idea to get some hands on experience with the Windows Dev Kit 2023 also known as Project Volterra.</description></item><item><title>Minikube, a lightweight Kubernetes-to-go!</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/minikube/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 13:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/minikube/</guid><description>From time-to-time I find myself tinkering with Kubernetes. I love the idea that I can create any type of workload (e.g. a simple webapp or a backend service), pick it up and put it somewhere else to run. Not having to care if it is in the cloud or on an on-premise cluster. However developing your application, testing its core in a local docker container and then deploying it to kubernetes can sometimes be cumberstone.</description></item><item><title>Real world mocking! Http Service testing in C# using Wiremock.Net</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/wiremock_net/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 14:09:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/wiremock_net/</guid><description>At Xpirit we have a culture of never ending learning. One of the best ways of learning new things, is by doing it. To take the plunge and do the deep dive.
In this case my colleague Kristoff Riebbels learned me some new tricks by introducing me into the world of WireMock.Net. Together we wrote a magazine article for Xpirit Magazine #13.
In this blog post I want to share this article with you.</description></item><item><title>Just do it! Work on your certifications.</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 15:08:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</guid><description>If you asked me 5 years ago if I would do any Microsoft exam, I would have told you that getting certified is something that you need to do at the start of your career. Besides that I would have told you that once your work experience and technical influence increases, you can rely on your seniority. I have to admit that for a long time I could get away with using the correct buzzwords at the correct moment supported by a certain arrogance.</description></item><item><title>Over-The-Air device update - IoT with C#</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/ota-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 12:32:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/ota-update/</guid><description>Developing solutions for IoT devices can be a challenging task, this can also apply for getting a device at its final destination in order to do its job. When time passes by, it is likely that either requirements or conditions are changing and that the device is not capable anymore of doing its job. In other words, it needs to be updated. This is where the real problems may start. In many cases devices are not physically accessible or there are simply too many devices in the field to do manual updates.</description></item><item><title>Techorama Antwerp 2022, human connection</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</guid><description>Techorama is a conference that has long been on my list of conferences to attend, but for some reason I never went. Looking back I think I had this idea that world class conferences could only be held in the US (or in a place far-far away from home) with thousands of visitors. I was dead wrong. What the organizers understood perfectly is that in order to have a world class conference, you should offer the same smooth, convenient and rich experience with the very best speakers, but then at a smaller scale.</description></item><item><title>Register ESP32 to DPS &amp; IoT hub - IoT with C#</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/iot-nanoframework-dps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 21:09:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/iot-nanoframework-dps/</guid><description>In my previous post I flashed my ESP32 with the nanoframework.net, allowing me to write C# code in Visual Studio with all bells and whistles. As life goes&amp;hellip; the device landed in my drawer until this week where I had some time to experiment. This time I wanted to hook up the device to Azure IoT hub using the Device Provisioning Service (DPS) which brings me one step closer to my goal, performing device updates over-the-air&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>From 0 to 100 in 30 minutes - IoT with C#</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/prepare-for-iot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 20:28:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/prepare-for-iot/</guid><description>My interest for the Internet of Things (IoT) was sparked many moons ago, way before the name was born. Back in the days I wrote software for PalmOS devices, and I was intrigued by having raw processor power in my Pocket. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, back then we where talking Megahertz instead of Gigahertz and Kilobyte instead of Gigabyte. Having such limitations in processing power and memory tickled my creativity. When I had the opportunity to control hardware (gps, electronic locks etc) using the little devices I was sold.</description></item><item><title>Running a persistent SQL Server in Docker</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/persistent-sql-docker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 17:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/persistent-sql-docker/</guid><description>In IT we always want to work with the latest and greatest, it&amp;rsquo;s in our DNA to explore new technologies. From time-to-time you get confronted with legacy technologies, robust but boring. One of such things is a piece of software I wrote more than 15 years ago for a friend. It was an application using a SQL Server database that controlled a couple of weighing terminals connected over RS232. Controlling machines is every geek&amp;rsquo;s dream.</description></item><item><title>Note to self: localhost in kestrel is localhost</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/localhost_in_kestrel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 17:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/localhost_in_kestrel/</guid><description>In one of the projects I&amp;rsquo;m involved in, I ran into a problem. In this project we are building a solution that is running on a Linux based Edge Device connected to Azure. On the Edge device, a k3s cluster hosts a number of services required by the solution. In order to be able to develop and debug on a Linux environment, I equiped my system with Hyper-V, an internal NAT switch and a fresh copy of Ubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes you need to reboot...</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</guid><description>Almost a year ago I created this blog&amp;hellip; I mean not exactly this blog, but its predecessor &amp;ldquo;blog.somethingazure.com&amp;rdquo;. I thought that the name did match the content. Fast Forward a couple of months in time&amp;hellip;. I learned that my job as Azure Coding Architect involved quite a few more technology areas than just Azure. Furthermore I was not happy with the look-and-feel of the blog; it was visually not attractive. Time for a major overhaul!</description></item><item><title>Multi-staged GitHub Pipeline</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 19:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</guid><description>At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m working on some infrastructure pipelines to build and deploy Azure infrastructure for one of our clients. For me a cool project as I&amp;rsquo;m learning to work with technologies such as Bicep and GitHub actions. In this project we use GitHub actions for the CI/CD process. In this process every time a pull request is merged in the main branch, an automated build, test and deployment process is triggered.</description></item><item><title>Certification Renewal</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</guid><description>When Microsoft introduced the new role based certifaction paths, a new expiration policy was set as well. After two years (as of july 2021, one year) the certification will expire, and you have to renew it in order to keep it.
At the time, I was among the first people who passed the new certifications and back then the new expiration policy was unclear. There was no information on how to renew the certifications and costs involved, until a few weeks ago&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>DevOps All the Way</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/devops-all-the-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/devops-all-the-way/</guid><description>In Practice what you preach I wrote that I decided to host my blog on the Azure platform, using Hugo as content management system, Blob Storage and Azure CDN for hosting the blog. The only thing lacking is a workflow of writing content, approving it and publishing it on the web.
As I work for a company that specialized on Azure and DevOps, I decided to take the plunge and go DevOps all the way.</description></item><item><title>Practice what you preach!</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 10:14:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</guid><description>When I decided to start blogging again, I knew I wanted to talk about the things I face, working with Azure. In the past I used to blog as well, back then I blogged on my Journey into CRM which I started in 2014.
In 2014 the state of technology was much different; one would use WordPress (or similar). The main choice was host it yourself or host it at a hosting provider.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>You have found my personal blog. This blog will be focused around Microsoft Azure technologies, hence the name &amp;ldquo;something Azure&amp;rdquo;. Let me introduce myself, my name is Bas van de Sande and I work as an Azure Coding Architect at Xpirit in the Netherlands.
As part of my daily job, I offer technical guidance, advice and hands-on assistance for a large number of (global) companies in various industries.
I have been working with Microsoft technologies since 1995 in various technical roles, since that time I have seen a large number of technologies passing by (Visual Studio technologies, SQL Server, BizTalk, Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>