<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/</link><description>Recent content on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sometimes you need to reboot...</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</guid><description>Almost a year ago I created this blog&amp;hellip; I mean not exactly this blog, but its predecessor &amp;ldquo;blog.somethingazure.com&amp;rdquo;. I thought that the name did match the content. Fast Forward a couple of months in time&amp;hellip;. I learned that my job as Azure Coding Architect involved quite a few more technology areas than just Azure. Furthermore I was not happy with the look-and-feel of the blog; it was visually not attractive. Time for a major overhaul!</description></item><item><title>Multi-staged GitHub Pipeline</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 19:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</guid><description>At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m working on some infrastructure pipelines to build and deploy Azure infrastructure for one of our clients. For me a cool project as I&amp;rsquo;m learning to work with technologies such as Bicep and GitHub actions. In this project we use GitHub actions for the CI/CD process. In this process every time a pull request is merged in the main branch, an automated build, test and deployment process is triggered.</description></item><item><title>Certification Renewal</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</guid><description>When Microsoft introduced the new role based certifaction paths, a new expiration policy was set as well. After two years (as of july 2021, one year) the certification will expire, and you have to renew it in order to keep it.
At the time, I was among the first people who passed the new certifications and back then the new expiration policy was unclear. There was no information on how to renew the certifications and costs involved, until a few weeks ago&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>DevOps All the Way</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/devops-all-the-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/devops-all-the-way/</guid><description>In Practice what you preach I wrote that I decided to host my blog on the Azure platform, using Hugo as content management system, Blob Storage and Azure CDN for hosting the blog. The only thing lacking is a workflow of writing content, approving it and publishing it on the web.
As I work for a company that specialized on Azure and DevOps, I decided to take the plunge and go DevOps all the way.</description></item><item><title>Practice what you preach!</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 10:14:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</guid><description>When I decided to start blogging again, I knew I wanted to talk about the things I face, working with Azure. In the past I used to blog as well, back then I blogged on my Journey into CRM which I started in 2014.
In 2014 the state of technology was much different; one would use WordPress (or similar). The main choice was host it yourself or host it at a hosting provider.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>You have found my personal blog. This blog will be focused around Microsoft Azure technologies, hence the name &amp;ldquo;something Azure&amp;rdquo;. Let me introduce myself, my name is Bas van de Sande and I work as an Azure Coding Architect at Xpirit in the Netherlands.
As part of my daily job, I offer technical guidance, advice and hands-on assistance for a large number of (global) companies in various industries.
I have been working with Microsoft technologies since 1995 in various technical roles, since that time I have seen a large number of technologies passing by (Visual Studio technologies, SQL Server, BizTalk, Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>