<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to prepare for the Azure Cybersecurity Architect SC-100 exam</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 13:18:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/sc100/</guid><description>Frustration! If one word should describe the learning experience using Microsoft Learn (other words could have been: indigestable, wut?!, uncohesive etcetera). I have never encountered a Microsoft Learning path that was so hard to digest. Then you could ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Is the subject that hard?&amp;rdquo;. It is not the subject, it is the way the self-study was written. In this blog post, I will share the way I prepared for this exam.</description></item><item><title>Just do it! Work on your certifications.</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 15:08:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification/</guid><description>If you asked me 5 years ago if I would do any Microsoft exam, I would have told you that getting certified is something that you need to do at the start of your career. Besides that I would have told you that once your work experience and technical influence increases, you can rely on your seniority. I have to admit that for a long time I could get away with using the correct buzzwords at the correct moment supported by a certain arrogance.</description></item><item><title>Over-The-Air device update - IoT with C#</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/ota-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 12:32:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/ota-update/</guid><description>Developing solutions for IoT devices can be a challenging task, this can also apply for getting a device at its final destination in order to do its job. When time passes by, it is likely that either requirements or conditions are changing and that the device is not capable anymore of doing its job. In other words, it needs to be updated. This is where the real problems may start. In many cases devices are not physically accessible or there are simply too many devices in the field to do manual updates.</description></item></channel></rss>