<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 15:35:43 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick tip: Get in control by using your GitHub context</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/github-context/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 15:35:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/github-context/</guid><description>GitHib actions and workflows are very powerful by nature. They help me to build and deploy my Azure environments, without having me to do all the tedious and errorprone work. I create a pull request, have it peer reviewed and once approved my environments are provisoned the way I envisioned it. This is also the case at my current assignment for a large organization. Last year the organization decided that a new change management system (which name I refuse to pronounce) should handle all changes.</description></item><item><title>Note to self: fix invalid GitHub credentials in VSCode</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/gitcredentials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 20:58:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/gitcredentials/</guid><description>From time to time I start working on projects for new customers. As soon as I start I receive an invitation from Github to join the customer&amp;rsquo;s Github organization. Most of the organization have a SAML based single sign on (SSO). After joining the organization using my personal Github account, I&amp;rsquo;m able to work on the repositories on which I have access. So far so good&amp;hellip;
Then the moment comes that I need to clone the repository, which can be a hassle from time-to-time.</description></item><item><title>Multi-staged GitHub Pipeline</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 19:46:30 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/mutistage-gh-pipeline/</guid><description>At the moment I&amp;rsquo;m working on some infrastructure pipelines to build and deploy Azure infrastructure for one of our clients. For me a cool project as I&amp;rsquo;m learning to work with technologies such as Bicep and GitHub actions. In this project we use GitHub actions for the CI/CD process. In this process every time a pull request is merged in the main branch, an automated build, test and deployment process is triggered.</description></item></channel></rss>