<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>general on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in general on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Techorama Antwerp 2022, human connection</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 16:15:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/techorama/</guid><description>Techorama is a conference that has long been on my list of conferences to attend, but for some reason I never went. Looking back I think I had this idea that world class conferences could only be held in the US with thousands of visitors (in a place far-far away from home). I was dead wrong. What the organizers understood perfectly is that in order to have a world class conference, you should offer the same smooth, convenient and rich experience with the very best speakers, but then at a smaller scale.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes you need to reboot...</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</guid><description>Almost a year ago I created this blog&amp;hellip; I mean not exactly this blog, but its predecessor &amp;ldquo;blog.somethingazure.com&amp;rdquo;. I thought that the name did match the content. Fast Forward a couple of months in time&amp;hellip;. I learned that my job as Azure Coding Architect involved quite a few more technology areas than just Azure. Furthermore I was not happy with the look-and-feel of the blog; it was visually not attractive. Time for a major overhaul!</description></item><item><title>Certification Renewal</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</guid><description>When Microsoft introduced the new role based certifaction paths, a new expiration policy was set as well. After two years (as of july 2021, one year) the certification will expire, and you have to renew it in order to keep it.
At the time, I was among the first people who passed the new certifications and back then the new expiration policy was unclear. There was no information on how to renew the certifications and costs involved, until a few weeks ago&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>You have found my personal blog. This blog will be focused around Microsoft Azure technologies, hence the name &amp;ldquo;something Azure&amp;rdquo;. Let me introduce myself, my name is Bas van de Sande and I work as an Azure Coding Architect at Xpirit in the Netherlands.
As part of my daily job, I offer technical guidance, advice and hands-on assistance for a large number of (global) companies in various industries.
I have been working with Microsoft technologies since 1995 in various technical roles, since that time I have seen a large number of technologies passing by (Visual Studio technologies, SQL Server, BizTalk, Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>