<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sometimes you need to reboot...</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:31:42 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/reboot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Almost a year ago I created this blog&amp;hellip; I mean not exactly this blog, but its predecessor &amp;ldquo;blog.somethingazure.com&amp;rdquo;.
I thought that the name did match the content. Fast Forward a couple of months in time&amp;hellip;. I learned that my job as Azure Coding Architect involved quite a few more technology areas than just Azure. Furthermore I was not happy with the look-and-feel of the blog; it was visually not attractive. Time for a major overhaul!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:20:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>You have found my personal blog. This blog will be focused around Microsoft Azure technologies, hence the name &amp;ldquo;something Azure&amp;rdquo;. Let me introduce myself, my name is Bas van de Sande and I work as an Azure Coding Architect at &lt;a href="https://www.xpirit.com">&lt;strong>Xpirit&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> in the Netherlands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of my daily job, I offer technical guidance, advice and hands-on assistance for a large number of (global) companies in various industries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working with Microsoft technologies since 1995 in various technical roles, since that time I have seen a large number of technologies passing by (Visual Studio technologies, SQL Server, BizTalk, Microsoft.Net, SharePoint, Dynamics CE etc). In one of my former jobs I have been doing product development on the Dynamics CE platform annd back then I used to blog very actively on my journey into CRM. Over the years I came to realize, that the continuous story of my life is system integration.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>