<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azure on Azure Coding Architect</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in azure on Azure Coding Architect</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 21:09:06 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azurecodingarchitect.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Register ESP32 to DPS &amp; IoT hub - IoT with C#</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/iot-nanoframework-dps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 21:09:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/iot-nanoframework-dps/</guid><description>In my previous post I flashed my ESP32 with the nanoframework.net, allowing me to write C# code in Visual Studio with all bells and whistles. As life goes&amp;hellip; the device landed in my drawer until this week where I had some time to experiment. This time I wanted to hook up the device to Azure IoT hub using the Device Provisiong Service (DPS) which brings me one step closer to my goal, performing device updates over-the-air&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Certification Renewal</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 19:30:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/certification-renewal/</guid><description>When Microsoft introduced the new role based certifaction paths, a new expiration policy was set as well. After two years (as of july 2021, one year) the certification will expire, and you have to renew it in order to keep it.
At the time, I was among the first people who passed the new certifications and back then the new expiration policy was unclear. There was no information on how to renew the certifications and costs involved, until a few weeks ago&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Practice what you preach!</title><link>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 10:14:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://azurecodingarchitect.com/posts/practice-what-you-preach/</guid><description>When I decided to start blogging again, I knew I wanted to talk about the things I face, working with Azure. In the past I used to blog as well, back then I blogged on my Journey into CRM which I started in 2014.
In 2014 the state of technology was much different; one would use WordPress (or similar). The main choice was host it yourself or host it at a hosting provider.</description></item></channel></rss>